when you look at some of the conflict
and i think we need to start there i
know prudential is very focused on asia
it's very focused also on africa as a
smaller hub that could become bigger but
i guess the market turmoil because of
the second and third round effects
should not be underestimated in the
market no i mean the events are
obviously horrific and i think they're
you know as is your opening comments
they're starting on uh you're creating
volatility and political tensions
globally um
to your earlier point we don't have
exposure to
you know europe let alone russia and
ukraine that's not where we do business
we do business now exclusively in asia
and africa so the secondary effects you
see there are market volatility
potential further acceleration of
inflation those sorts of dynamics but
we're on the other side of the world of
that of that uh you know current crisis
yeah is there anything that that you
worry about in terms of the markets
freezing up i mean liv you lived through
the 08 crisis i did and so could we see
anything similar there no there's a big
fun position a lot of lot better
coordination with global you know the
the equivalent of central bankers
there's you know excellent liquidity for
example if you look at the
bank of england u.s relationship those
you know those are strong and historic
uh more cooperation with asian key
central bank figures uh hong kong mas
and things you know there's they're uh i
think that model is much more
sophisticated than it was in oh 808 it
was relationship based i think this has
now got good relationships but also much
more technical structure
so uh that doesn't mean you won't get
volatility right but and i think it
changes what people want to invest in
and it's a risk off as you see you know
we're we've been a
liquid we're seeing that sometimes as a
european stock and we get hit by you
know by uh volatility noise but
you know in spite of uh growing sales
eight percent new business profits 13
and as you said you know operating
income plus 16 and you know uh it's
the risk-off piece i think is where
you'll see the market go now because
that's the consumer sentiment not just
the the trader sentiment and my
prudential is now really an
asian-focused business and actually it's
really important for investors and
people you know that watch us to realize
that what role will africa play in this
at the moment it's quite small how much
it is so africa is uh our future right
so it you know the key uh when you when
you're a ceo of 170 plus year old
institution there's a bit of a
stakeholder mindset to it can you make
it better than you found it and there's
a responsibility to position things for
you know future leadership so
you know i was uh when i when i joined
prudential uh this is showing my age
our asia business was less than three
million pounds of earnings contribution
and it was categorized as other
geographically yeah and you know now you
see the the sort of numbers that you
know it's producing it's one of the
largest businesses in the region and
it's grown you know very dramatically
africa has got the same potential but
over a longer time frame and the team's
on their years i don't think it's that
long i think it'll go faster
everything about our industry is
accelerating faster consumer preference
regulatory capital models you know
technology has made learning faster if
you're a regulator a consumer a
competitor you know uh so i i think the
the it's it's about the political
development there but it's the a young
continent and it's got tremendous upside
and and tremendous need for there you
know there aren't governments that have
uh retirement savings or health
protection uh you know schemes at scale
and so that's what we do
mike it's very clear that when you look
at what's happening with russia and
ukraine so of course it's always the
loss of life that we think about but
there's also now become an economic war
between the us the uk certain parts of
europe and russia do you worry that
we're going to see some kind of
geopolitical
you know concerns being transferred with
china and how do you to prevent
something happening if geopolitically
china becomes more aggressive yeah i
think the the lens always with china
that's important is is what's in their
long-term best interest they're they're
not as short you know they don't tend to
react short term if you look at their
history and certainly the history of
their current leadership so
their moves i think personally you know
less than a corporate view we're are
always towards
what's what's the greater benefit of
china the the key for for china now
you've seen they've they've produced
lower gdp yep uh growth rate forecast
which is still in excess of five percent
and growth is going to be hard to find
globally again i think we're positioning
the markets that'll have it but five
percent's an excellent number for the
size of the economy but it's critical to
the success of the economy so that i
think that's first and foremost the lens
for their government now
so you know the they're seeing what's
happening to an isolationist
you know russia now and i and i don't
think that's if you're the smart
political leadership and they have you
know very talented people they're going
to look at that and say we don't need
any of this noise we don't need any of
these challenges um you know they want
to grow the economy and you do that by
being a part of the world economy not
separating yourselves mike you have a
joint venture actually in china with
city we do um is it is it does it make
sense taking it over completely um so i
i've been public uh you know
i would have loved to have bought the
whole thing it's up
24 this year it's grown
almost 40 percent here in both earnings
and in in uh uh it's key metrics since
since i've been ceo it's an incredibly
successful business now so they enjoy it
too
it has a footprint across all of asia
excuse me all of china it has 84 or 85
percent of china's economy and it's got
uh and the civic's been a great partner
so we'd love to have it um
it's working very well as it is now and
they're a sophisticated partner
in dealing with china including the
political questions you're asking
they're a great partner